# Jorge García

jorest1994@gmail.com

Phone: (+502)40500072

www.linkedin.com/in/jorge-garcia-45545790

Portfolio : <a href="https://jorest.github.io/">https://jorest.github.io/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Quality-oriented engineer, who likes to learn new things. I have experience working with multidisciplinary teams, with the ability to communicate and discuss new ideas. Experienced mainly as a programmer, and passionate about game design especially game mechanics.

Please feel free to check my technical skills and certificates on Linkedin.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Self-taught
- Creative
- Team player
- An analytical frame of mind
- knowledgeable in gaming trends

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Freelance Web Game Developer,** Koji Social Mini Apps Platform **11/2019-Present** 

- Developing web-based games using javascript.
- The games are responsive and let the end-user change any asset.

## **IT Engineer,** Ericsson

03/2019-09/2019

- Worked under the supervision of senior IT Engineers to implement, test, deploy, and support new features and fixes.
- I have worked on a telecom system, using a proprietary version of java.

Worked both with Git and SVN.

## VR Developer, Optimus View

03/2018-10/2018

- Developed and tested VR applications using Unity, (C#) to showcase real-estate properties.
- Requirement gathering and customer liaising
- Optimized the frame per second, to be able to run the projects in lower spec machines.
- Worked with graphic designers, to make the features and aesthetics work well together.

## Game Designer, Lion Works

03/2015-10/2015

- Independent contractor as Game Designer for El Chavo Playbook Acalulpo
- Cooperated with programmers, artists, and management personal.
- Made fast changes on the game design, based on feedback, branding rules, or expert opinion.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Computer Science Engineering**

01/2013-12/2018

Universidad del Valle de Guatemala.

Academic achievements:

- distinguished student 2015
- distinguished student 2016
- Kept a Scholarship for five years

## **Computer Science Engineering Abroad**

07/2016-02/2017

University of the Basque Country, Spain.

Exchange student for a semester

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- ETS TOEFL 102/120
- Linkedin Game Design Foundations (1,2,3)